Guide to the NURTUREart records CBHM.0025
Center for Brooklyn History
- Series 2: Exhibits
  - Sub-series 2.2: Administrative and planning materials
    - Rational Formal, 2015 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - What It Was, 2015 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Deep Time, 2015 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Gabriela Salazar: My Lands are Islands, 2015 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - SEXTANT, 2015 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - VIDEOROVER: Season 8, 2015 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Interference, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Open Call Jury, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Our Crazy Life, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Summer Anagram, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Dead Lands, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Prime, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Vanessa Albury: Arctic, Future Relics, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Codes for Conduct, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Interference, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - Single Channel, 2016 (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - 1402 Seok-Dong, 2017 (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - She is alone, 2017 (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - Voices Need Heros, 2017 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Only the Finest of Fifis, 2017 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Archive of Affect, 2017 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Summer Flavors, 2018 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Christie Neptune: Unpacking Sameness, 2018 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Object Intimacies, 2018 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Aesthetic Behavior; Development Sequences, 2019 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Promotional signs, 2009-2012 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Sub-series 2.3: Emerging Curators' Program exhibit proposals
    - 2003-2005 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - 2005-2007 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - 2007 (Box 70, Folder 1-4)
    - 2007-2009 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - 2009-2010 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - 2010-2013 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - 2013-2016 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Emerging Curators' Program media, circa 2003-2016 (Box 72, Item 1-63)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      VHS tapes are unavailable due to technical limitations.
  - Sub-series 2.4: Promotional materials and clippings
    - Exhibit postcards and brochures, 1998-2003 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Exhibit postcards and brochures, 2004-2007 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Exhibit postcards and brochures, 2008-2010 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Exhibit postcards and brochures, 2010-2012 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Exhibit postcards and brochures, 2012 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Exhibit postcards and brochures, 2012-2014 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Exhibit postcards and brochures, 2016-2018 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Exhibit postcards and brochures, Education, 2009-2019 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Gallery programs, 2010-2015 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 2006-2014 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Gallery and exhibition documents, circa 2004-2010 (Box 73, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Administrative Records
  Series 3: Administrative records is arranged in eight sub-series:
  Sub-series 3.1: Board minutes is arranged chronologically with the exception of the Web Committee minutes, which appear at the end.
  Sub-series 3.2: Organizational documents is not arranged.
  Sub-series 3.3: Financial documents is arranged chronologically.
  Sub-series 3.4: Grants, donations and fundraising is grouped by topic. Grants appear first, arranged alphabetically, followed by records arranged chronologically.
  Sub-series 3.5: Strategic planning and marketing is not arranged.
  Sub-series 3.6: Correspondence is not arranged.
  Sub-series 3.7 Employee files is arranged chronologically.
  Sub-series 3.8: Artifacts is not arranged.
  Series 3: Administrative records holds materials created in the day-to-day management of the gallery and staff. Board minutes and meeting agendas date from 1998-2019 and are both handwritten and typed. Organizational documents include NURTUREart by-laws, certificate of incorporation, and financial statements. This series also houses documents concerning fundraising for the gallery through grants, donations, sales, and fundraising events. Marketing plans, press releases, and the gallery's strategic plan dating circa 2011 are also included.
  - Sub-series 3.1: Board minutes
    - 1998-1999 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - 2000 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - 2001 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - 2002 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - 2003 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - 2004 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - 2005 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - 2006 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - 2007 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - 2008 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - 2009 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - 2010 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - 2011-2012 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 2013-2014 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 2015, 2019 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Web Committee minutes, circa 2003 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series 3.2: Organizational documents
    - By-laws, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, photocopy, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Conflict of Interest forms, 2000-2004 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 501 3C applications, 1997-1998 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Sublease agreements, 56 Bogart Street, 2012-2013 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Templates, 2003-2004 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - VENDEX questionnaire, circa 2010 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Sub-series 3.3: Financial documents
    - Financial statements, 2011-2018 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - New York State Charities Bureau, 2012-2013 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Sub-series 3.4: Grants, donations and fundraising
    - Altman Foundation, 2009-2012 (Box 77, Folder 1-2)
    - The Andy Warhol Foundation for the Visual Arts, 1998-2014 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Asian American Arts Centre, 2005 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - AT and T Foundation, 1996-1998 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - BTIG, 2015 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - The Barker Welfare Foundation, 2014 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - The Bay and Paul Foundation, 2012-2013 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - A Blade of Grass Foundation, 2012-2013 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Bloomberg L.P., 2009-2012 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Booth Ferris Foundation, 2014 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Brooklyn Arts Council, 2004-2008 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Brooklyn Arts Council, 2008-2014 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Brooklyn Community Foundation, 2011-2012 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Chase Manhattan, 1998 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Colgate-Palmolive Company, 2012-2014 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Consolidated Edison Compnay, 2012-2014 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Corporations outreach, 1998-2008 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - The Cowles Charitable Trust, 2006-2013 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Charles E. Culpepper Foundation, 1997 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Czech Center New York, 2014 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Dedalus Foundation, 2010-2012 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Deutsche Bank Foundation, 2013 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Dime Savings Bank, 2001 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Edelman, 2013-2014 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Elizabeth Firestone Graham Foundation, 2007-2014 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - étant donnés, 2004 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Foundation for Contemporary Arts, 2010-2014 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Furthermore, 2012-2013 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Gesso Foundation, 2011 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - The Golden Rule Foundation, 2013-2014 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Google, 2011 (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Greenwich Collection, 2010-2012 (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Harpo Foundation, 2014 (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - The Hearst Foundation, 2011 (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - The Heckscher Foundation for Children, 2012, 2012 (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Helena Rubinstein Foundation, 1997, 2008 (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - Ho Foundation, 2013-2015 (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - Hyde and Watson Foundation, 2013 (Box 78, Folder 20)
    - Independence Community Foundation, 2004-2009 (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - Jerome Foundation, 2007-2013 (Box 78, Folder 22)
    - Jewish Communal Fund, 2014-2015 (Box 78, Folder 23)
    - Joan Mitchell Foundation, 2002, 2012-2015 (Box 78, Folder 24)
    - Keith Haring Foundation, 2012 (Box 78, Folder 25)
    - The Lambent Foundation, 2013 (Box 78, Folder 26)
    - The Laura B. Vogler Foundation, Inc., 2012-2013 (Box 78, Folder 27)
    - Lily Auchincloss Foundation, 2003-2013 (Box 78, Folder 28)
    - Lower Manhattan Cultural Council, 2000-2002 (Box 78, Folder 29)
    - Lower Manhattan Cultural Council, 2000-2002 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - MADE Art, LLC, 2014-2015 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Mid Atlantic Arts Foundation, 2003-2004 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - The Milton and Sally Avery Arts Foundation, Inc., 2006-2015 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Morris P. Liebovitz Foundation, 2014 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Nathan Cummings Foundation, 1999 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 2009-2016 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - New York City Council, 2004-2016 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - New York City Department of Cultural Affairs, 2010-2011 (Box 79, Folder 9-10)
    - New York City Department of Cultural Affairs, 2012-2017 (Box 80, Folder 1-3)
    - New York Community Trust, 2011 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - New York State Council on the Arts, 2004-2015 (Box 80, Folder 5-6)
    - New York State Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation, 2006-2008 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - The Pollock-Krasner Foundation, Inc., 2010 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Puffin Foundation, 2006-2014 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Pfizer, 2008 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Robert Lehman Foundation, 2013-2014 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - The Robert Mapplethrope Foundation, 2013-2014 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Rush Philanthropic, 2010 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - The Scherman Foundation, 2013-2015 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - The Seth Sprague Educational and Charitable Foundation, 2014 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Stonewall Community Foundation, 2002 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - The Sulzberger Foundation, Inc., 2007 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Technology Donations, 2008, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - The Thelma S. Rodbell Charitable Foundation, 2012 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Treasure and Bond, 2013 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Trust for Mutual Understanding, 2014 (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - Walentas Family Foundation, 2013-2014 (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - Verizon Foundation, 2011 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - The Wolf Kahn and Emily Mason Foundation, 2010-2012 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - Individual Gifts, 2011-2015 (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - Nurturing the New, donation forms, 2003 (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - Nurturing the New, sales, 2004 (Box 81, Folder 21-22)
    - Nurturing the New, media, 2005 (Box 81, Folder 23)
    - Nurturing the New, sales, 2005 (Box 82, Folder 1-2)
    - Nurturing the New, yearbooks, 2005 (Box 88, Box 1-2)
    - Nurturing the New, yearbook, 2005 (Box 89, Box 1)
    - Nurturing the Edge, sales [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Nurturing the Edge, press, 2006 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Suggested donation signs, circa 2006-2012 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Raffle, circa 2006 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Casino Night, 2009 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Benifit, sales, 2010 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Spring Fundraiser, 2011 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Benefit Committee meeting notes, 2012 (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Benfit donation forms and contracts, 2013 (Box 82, Folder 11-12)
    - Benfit donations, 2013 (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Benefit, photos, 2013 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Benefit, dontaions and press, 2014 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Benefit Commitee minutes, 2015, undated (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Benefit stickers, 2017 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Grant prospects, 1998-2015 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Grant prospects, Education, circa 2005-2011 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series 3.5: Strategic planning and marketing
    - NURTUREart history with exhibition and programs list, 1998-2007 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Strategic planning, circa 2011 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Marketing Plan, 2008 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Press prospects and layouts, circa 1998-2008 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Press releases, 1998-2004 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Golden Age [book of essays], 2014 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Slide digitization project, 2004 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Signs, oversize, circa 2015 (Folder Flat File)
  - Sub-series 3.6: Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1998-2015 (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Sub-series 3.7: Employee files
    - Lists of employees and volunteers [?], circa 2004 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Carol Salmanson, 2005-2007 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Artist-in-Residence, 2009-2010 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Molly O'Brien, 2011-2016 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Education employee documents, 2016 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Job descriptions, 2016 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Artist residency, 2017 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series 3.8: Artifacts
    - NURTUREart t-shirt, possibly promotional, circa 2012 (Box 89, Item 1)
    - T-shirt, circa 2012 (Box 89, Item 2)
    - Embosser, circa 1998 (Box 89, Item 3)
    - Stamp, circa 1998 (Box 89, Item 4)
- Series 4: Education
  Conditions Governing Access
  Due to sensitive personal information some folders in Series 4: Education are restricted until 2075.
  Series 4: Education is arranged chronologically.
  See series 2 for additional exhibit materials created for Project Curate.
  Series 4: Education includes materials created by students and NURTUREart staff as part of NURTUREarts' Education Outreach Program. Materials include teaching materials and notes, evaluations, student response sheets, student artwork, and documentation for Project Curate.
  - Project Curate, 2010-2011 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Education outreach program, general infomation, 2010-2015 (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Juan Morel Campos Secondary School [RESTRICTED], 2010-2017 (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Charles O. Dewey Middle School, 2010-2012, 2016 (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - buildOn, 2011 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Common Core NYC/NYS curriculums, circa 2012 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2013 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - P.S. 147 The Isaac Remsen School [RESTRICTED], 2013-2015 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - School signage, circa 2013-2015 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Project Curate, 2014-2015 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - P.S. 147 The Isaac Remsen School, Art Explorers Club [RESTRICTED], circa 2015 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Juan Morel Campos Secondary School, BRIC Brooklyn Youth Media Festival [RESTRICTED], 2015 (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Photo release templates, circa 2015 (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Resident training, circa 2015 (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Department of Education purchase orders and contract work, 2015-2018 (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Juan Morel Campos Secondary School [RESTRICTED], 2015-2017 (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - P.S. 147 The Isaac Remsen School [RESTRICTED], 2015-2017 (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Youth Advisory Board [RESTRICTED], 2017 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Juan Morel Campos Secondary School, assesments, 2017-2018 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Proposal and Student artwork, Framewerk, 2017 (Box 91, Folder 2-3)
  - P.S. 147 The Isaac Remsen School, chart, circa 2017 (Folder Flat File)